Inventory of the Jan Rowiński collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Jan Rowiński collection
1967
2007C46
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 9 oversize folders (8.4 linear feet)
Broadsides, flyers, and posters issued by Red Guards relating to the Chinese Cultural Revolution.
Rowinski, Jan
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Chronology
May 11, 1936 Born in the village of Kielpiny, in northern Poland
1954-1955 Studied Chinese language at the University of Beijing
1955-1960 Studied at the Diplomatic Institute, Beijing
1960-1965 Worked in the China Department of the Polish Foreign Ministry
1961 Received an MA from the Main School of Foreign Service, Warsaw
1965 Completed a PhD in the History of International Relations, Warsaw
1965-1968 Served as the II and then I Secretary of the Polish Embassy in Beijing
1969-1993 Conducted research and taught at the Polish Institute of International Relations, Warsaw
1985-1989 Served as the editor-in-chief of Problems of the Far East, quarterly publication of the Polish Academy of Sciences
1987 Completed a Habilitacja (post PhD) in Political Science, Warsaw
1993-1995 Served in the Foreign Ministry, research and planning deprtment
1995-2001 Served in the Polish embassy in Beijing (as deputy ambassador, minister)
2001-2011 Worked as a professor of political science at University of Warsaw, and in the Institute of International Relations
2011 Retired after a long career of writing: 250 essays and articles, and several monographs, including 4 volumes on the Cultural Revolution and 17 volumes on Chinese foreign policy during from 1949 to 1985
Scope and Content of Collection
Broadsides, flyers, and posters issued by Red Guards relating to the Chinese Cultural Revolution.
China--History--Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976.
- Broadsides and flyers, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - The Solid Evidence of History; Li shi de tie zheng (LìShǐ de TiěZhèng), comic monograph, 历史的铁证 (歷史的鐵証), 1967 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Workers' Daily: Revolutionary Rebellion Communication Stations Cannot Be Defeated, Cannot Be Toppled. Gong ren ri bao ge ming zao fan lian luo zhan shi ma bu dao cui bu kua de (GōngRén RìBào GéMìng ZàoFǎn LiánLuòZhàn Shì MàBùDǎo CuīBùKuǎ De), Workers' Daily, 工人日报革命造反联络站是骂不倒摧不垮的 (工人日報革命造反聯絡站是駡不倒摧不垮的), 1967 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Ren Ping Yi Shi Feng Lang Qi Ri Kan Hou Xiao Shi He Ren? (RènPíng YīShí Fēng Làng Qǐ Rì KānHòuXiào Shì HéRén?) Red Steel Army Magazine, 任凭一时风浪起日刊后笑是何人 (任憑一時風浪起日刊後笑是何人), 1967 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - During the Two Years of the Great Leap Forward, What Political Line were Tao Zhu and Zhao Ziyang Implementing While Working in the Countryside? Zai Da Yue Jin Liang Nian Jian, Tao Zhu, Zhao Ziyang Zai Nong Cun Gong Zuo Fang Mian Zhi Xing Shen Me Lu Xian (Zài Dà​Yuè​Jìn Liǎng NiánJiān Táo Zhù, Zhào​ Zǐ​yáng Zài NóngCūn GōngZuò FāngMiàn ZhíXíng ShénMe LùXiàn), Highest Instructions Newspaper, 在大跃进两年间陶铸，赵紫阳在农村工作方面执行什么路线？(在大躍進兩年間陶鑄,趙紫陽在農村工作方面執行甚麼路線), 1967 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Hold High the Great Red Banner of Mao Zedong, Attack Fiercely on the Reactionary Path of Capitalist Shanghai Municipal Committee, Conference Special Edition. Gao Ju Mao Zedong Si Xiang Wei Ta Hong Qi Xiang Shanghai Shi Wei Zi Chan Jie Ji Fan Dong Lu Xian Meng Lie Kai Huo Da Hui Te Kan (GāoJǔ Máo​ Zé​dōng SīXiǎng WěiDà HóngQí Xiàng Shàng​hǎi​ ShìWěi ZīChǎnJiēJí FǎnDòng LùXiàn MěngLiè KāiHuǒ DàHuì TèKān), 高举毛泽东思想伟大红旗向上海市委资产阶级反动路线猛烈开火大会特刊 (高舉毛澤東思想偉大紅旗向上海市委資產階級反動路線猛烈開火大會特刊), 1966 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Proletariat Revolutionaries Act to Totally Destroy the Wan Zhang Anti-Party Fraction. Wu Chan Jie Ji Ge Ming Pai Ji Ji Xing Dong Qi Lai Che Di Cui Hui Wan Zhang Fan Dang Ji Tuan (WúChǎnJiēJí GéMìng Pài JīJí XíngDòng QǐLai ChèDǐ CuīKuǎ WànZhāng FǎnDǎng JíTuán), 無产阶级革命派积极行动起来彻底摧垮万张反党集团 (無產階級革命派積極行動起來徹底摧垮萬張反黨集團), 1967 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Cut the Chief Culprit Who Damaged the Four Cleanups Movement in Hebei Cities--Three-Anti Element Li Jiebo. Dao Gua Po Huai He Bei Sheng Cheng Shi Si Qing De Huo Shou--San Fan Fen Zi Li Jie Bo (DāoGuǎ PòHuài Hé​běi​ Shěng ChéngShì Sì​qīng de HuòShǒu - SānFǎn FènZǐ Lǐ JiéBó, 刀剐破坏河北省城市四清的祸首——三反分子李颉伯 (刀剮破壞河北省城市四清的禍首 -------- 三反份子李頡伯), 1967 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Bulletin, Bu Gao (BùGào), 布告 (佈告), 1967 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Smash the Dog Head of Whoever Opposes Chairman Mao. Shei Fan Dui Mao Zhu Xi Jiu Za Lan Shei De Gou Tou (Shéi FǎnDuì Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí Jiù ZáLàn Shéi de GǒuTóu ). 谁反对毛主席就砸烂谁的狗头 (誰反對毛主席就砸爛誰的狗頭), 1967 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - 1967 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Preparation Committee for Grand Coalition of Beijing Revolutionary Workers Announcement. Beijing Ge Ming Zhi Gong Da Lian He Chou Bei Wei Yuan Hui Tong Gao (Běi​Jīng GéMìng ZhíGōng Dà LiánHé ChóuBèi WěiYuánHuì TōngGào), 北京革命职工大联合筹备委员会通告 (北京革命職工大聯合籌備委員會通告), 1967 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Look, the Repulsive Soul of Liu Shao Qi. Kan Liu Shao Qi Chou E de Ling Hun (Kàn, Liú​ Shào​qí de Chǒu'è LíngHún), 看, 刘少奇的丑恶灵魂 (看, 劉少奇的醜惡靈魂), 1967 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Liu Shaoqi and the Gao Gou Incident. Liu Shao Qi yu Gao Gou Shi Jian (Liú​ Shào​qí yú Gāo Gōu ShìJiàn), 刘少奇与高沟事件 (劉少奇與高溝事件), 1967 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Li Jiebo, Capitalist Roader in Power in the Party. Li Jiebo Shi Dang Nei Zou Zi Ben Zhu Yi Dao Lu de Dang Quan Pai (Lǐ JiéBó Shì DǎngNèi Zǒu ZīBěnZhǔYì DàoLù de DāngQuánPài) 李颉伯是党内走资本主义道路的当权派 (李頡伯是黨內走資本主義道路的當權派), 1967 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Joint Statement on the Problem of Tai Fang. Guan Yu Tai Fang Wen Ti de Lian He Sheng Ming (GuānYú Tài Fǎng WènTí de LiánHé ShēngMíng), 关于太纺问题的联合声明 (關於太紡問題的聯合聲明), 1967 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Look, the Black Materials of the Sichuan Whole Revolution Rebel Faction. Kan Si Chuan Sheng Ge Chou Ban Zheng Ge Ge Ming Zao Fan Pai de Hei Cai Liao (Kàn, Sì​Chuān​Shěng Gé ChóuBàn ZhěngGè GéMìng ZàoFǎnPài de HēiCáiLiào). 看，四川省革筹办整个革命造反派的黑材料 (看, 四川省革籌辦整個革命造反派的黑材料), 1967 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Conference Proceedings, Hui Kan (HuìKān). 会刊 (會栞), 1967 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - He Bei Province, Tian Jin Proletarian Revolutionaries Criticize the Biggest Capitalist Roaders in Power--Liu, Deng, Tao and Their Lackeys, Conference Proceedings. He Bei Sheng, Tian Jin Shi Wu Chan Jie Ji Ge Ming Pai Pi Dou Dang Nei Zui Da de Zou Zi Ben Zhu Yi Dao Lu Dang Quan Pai Liu, Deng, Tao Ji Qi Zhao Ya Da Hui Hui Kan (Hé​běi​ Shěng Tiān​Jīn​Shì WúChǎnJiēJí GéMìng Pài PīDòu DǎngNèi ZuìDà de Zǒu ZīBěnZhǔYì DàoLù DāngQuánPài Liú, Dèng, Táo JíQí ZhǎoYá DàHuì HuìKān), 河北省，天津市无产阶级革命派批斗党内最大的走资本主义道路当权派刘，邓，陶及其爪牙大会会刊 (河北省天津市無產階級革命派批鬥黨內最大的走資本主義道路當權派劉, 鄧, 陶及其爪牙大會會栞), 1967 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Ten Crimes of Anti-Revolution Revisionist Lin Feng Who is Against CCP, Against Society and Against Maoist Thoughts. Fan Ge Ming Xiu Zheng Zhu Yi Fen Zi Lin Feng Fan Dang Fan She Hui Zhu Yi Fan Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang de Shi Da Zui Zhuang (FǎnGéMìng XiūZhèngZhǔYì FènZǐ Lín Fēng FǎnDǎng Fǎn ShèHuìZhǔYì Fǎn Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng de Shí Dà ZuìZhuàng), 反革命修正主义分子林枫反党反社会主义反毛泽东思想的十大罪状 (反革命修正主義份子林楓反黨反社會主義反毛澤東思想的十大罪狀), 1966 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Ten Crimes of Anti-Revolution Revisionist Shi Xi Min. Fan Ge Ming Xiu Zheng Zhu Yi Fen Zi Shi Xi Min Shi Da Zui Zhuang (FǎnGéMìng XiūZhèngZhǔYì FènZǐ Shí Xīmín Shí Dà ZuìZhuàng) 反革命修正主义分子石西民十大罪状 (反革命修正主義份子石西民十大罪狀), 1967 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Ten Crimes of Anti-Revolution Revisionist Xu Guang Xiao. Fan Ge Ming Xiu Zheng Zhu Yi Fen Zi Xu Guang Xiao de Shi Da Zui Zhuang (FǎnGéMìng XiūZhèngZhǔYì FènZǐ Xú Guāngxiāo de Shí Dà ZuìZhuàng) 反革命修正主义分子徐光霄的十大罪状 (反革命修正主義份子徐光霄的十大罪状), 1967 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Emergency in Henan, Two Seven Storm Edition. He Nan Gao Ji Er Qi Feng Bao Zhuan Ji (Hé​nán GàoJí èrQī FēngBào ZhuānJí), 河南告急二七风暴专辑 (河南告急二七風暴專輯), 1967 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Exposing the Big Conspiracy of Xiao Wang Dong. Chuo Chuan Xiao Wang Dong de Da Yin Mou (ChuōChuān Xiāo Wàngdōng de Dà YīnMóu), 戳穿肖望东的大阴谋 (戳穿肖望東的大陰謀), 1967 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Catch the Political Pickpocket Wang Ren Zhong. Zhuo Na Zheng Zhi Pa Shou Wang Ren Zhong, Di Er Ji (ZhuōNá ZhèngZhì PáShǒu Wáng Rènzhòng, Dì'èr Jí), 捉拿政治扒手王任重, 第二辑 (捉拿政治扒手王任重, 第二輯), 1966 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Good News: Cheer for the Birth of Shanghai People's Commune. Xi Bao: Re Lie Huan Hu Shang Hai Ren Min Gong She Dan Sheng (XǐBào RèLiè HuānHū Shàng​Hǎi RénMínGōngShè DànShēng), 喜报: 热烈欢呼上海人民公社诞生 (喜報熱烈歡呼人民公社誕生), 1967 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Why We Drove Away the So Called "Committee" Who Claims to Seize and Supervise (Henan Daily). Wo Men Wei Shen Me Gan Zou Suo Wei (WǒMen WèiShénMe GǎnZǒu SuǒWèi CháFēng JiānGuǎn (Hé​Nán RìBào> WěiYuánHuì),我们为什么趕走所谓查封监管《河南日报》委员会 (我們為什麼趕走所謂查封監管《河南日報》委員會), 1967 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Urgent Notice from Jing Gang Mountain. Jing Gang Shan Jin Ji Tong Gao (Jǐng​Gāng​Shān JǐnJí TōngGào), 井冈山紧急通告 (井岡山緊急通告), 1967 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Stick to Principles, Persevere In Solidarity. Jian Chi Yuan Ze, Jian Chi Tuan Jie (JiānChí YuánZé, JiānChí TuánJié), 坚持原则，坚持团结 (堅持原則堅持團結), 1967 (Box-folder 1:28)
- Posters, circa 1971 (Map case)
  Posters of Cultural Revolution subjects. Please use file of reference images in Box 1, Folder 29.
  - Poster image reference file (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Be Ready at All Times to Annihilate Enemy Invaders! Shi Ke Zhun Bei Zhe Jian Mie Lai Fan De Di Ren (ShíKèZhǔnBèi Zhe JiānMiè LáiFàn De DíRén), 时刻准备着歼灭来犯的敌人！(時刻準備著殲滅來犯的敵人)
  - Comrade Bethune's spirit, his utter devotion to others without any thought of self, was shown in his great sense of responsibility in his work and his great warm-heartedness towards all comrades and the people. Every Chinese Communist must learn from him. Mao Zedong. Bai Qiu En Tong Zhi Hao Bu Li Ji Zhuan Men Li Ren De Jing Shen Biao Xian Zai Ta Dui Gong Zuo De Ji Duan De Fu Ze Ren, Dui Tong Zhi Dui Ren Min De Ji Duan De Re Chen. Mei Ge Gong Chan Dang Yuan Dou Yao Xue Xi Ta. (Bái​ Qiú​'ēn TóngZhì HáoBù LìJǐ ZhuānMén LìRén De JīngShén BiǎoXiàn Zài Tā Duì GōngZuò De JíDuān De FùZéRèn, Duì TóngZhì Duì RénMín De JíDuān De RèChén. Měi Gè Gòng​Chǎn​Dǎng​Yuán Dōu Yào Xué​Xí Tā Máo​ Zé​dōng). 白求恩同志毫不利己专门利人的精神，表现在他对工作的极端的负责任，对同志对人民的极端的热忱。每个共产党员都要学习他。毛泽东 ( 白求恩白求恩白求恩白求恩專門利人的精神表現在他對工作的極端的負責任對同志對人民的極端的熱忱。 每個共產黨員都要學習他。 毛澤東)
  - Drive the old and new colonists out of Africa! Jiang Xin Lao Zhi Min Zhu Yi Zhe Gan Chu Fei Zhou Qu (Jiāng Xīn Lǎo ZhíMín ZhǔYì Zhě GǎnChū Fēi​Zhōu Qù). 将新老殖民主义者赶出非洲去！(將新老殖民主義者趕出非洲去!)
  - Strongly support the fight of the people of Asia, Africa and Latin America against imperialism. Jian Jue Zhi Chi Ya Zhou Fei Zhou La Ding Mei Zhou Ren Min De Fan Di Dou Zheng (JiānJué ZhīChí Yà​Zhōu Fēi​Zhōu Lā​Dīng​ Měi​Zhōu​ RénMín de FǎnDì DòuZhēng). 坚决支持亚洲非洲拉丁美洲人民的反帝斗争 (堅決支持亞洲非洲拉丁美洲人民的反帝鬥爭)
  - Learn the Sixteen Articles (Decision of the C.P.C. Central Committee Concerning the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution), be familiar with the Sixteen Articles, Use the Sixteen Articles. Xue Xi Shi Liu Tiao, Shu Xi Shi Liu Tiao, Yun Yong Shi Liu Tiao (XuéXí ShíLiù Tiáo, Shú​Xī ShíLiù Tiáo, Yùn​Yòng ShíLiù Tiáo). 学习十六条，熟悉十六条，运用十六条 ( 學習十六條, 熟悉十六條, 運用十六條。)
  - Commemorating the 25th anniversary of the publication of "Talks at the Yan'an Forum on Literature and Art." Swearing to defend, with our lives, chairman Mao's revolutionary line in literature. Ji Nian Zai Yan An Wen Yi Zuo Tan Hui Shang De Jiang Hua Fa Biao Er Shi Wu Zhou Nian Shi Si Han Wei Mao Zhu Xi De Wen Yi Lu Xian (JìNiàn Zài Yán​'ān WénYì ZuòTánHuì Shàng De JiǎngHuà FāBiǎo èrShíWǔ ZhōuNián ShìSǐ HànWèi Máo​ Zhǔ​xí De WénYì LùXiàn). 纪念《在延安文艺座谈会上的讲话》发表二十五周年 誓死捍卫毛主席的文艺路线 (紀念《在延安文藝座談會上的講話》發表二十五週年誓死捍衛毛主席的文藝路線)
  - The proletariat revolutionary party holds power tight! Wu Chan Jie Ji Ge Ming Pai Lao Wo Da Quan (WúChǎnJiēJí GéMìngPài Láo Wò DàQuán). 无产阶级革命派牢握大权！(無產階級革命派牢握大權!)
  - Work Hard to Build the Country with Industry and Thrift and By Self-Reliant Efforts. Zi Li Geng Sheng Fa Fen Tu Qiang Jian Ku Fen Dou Qin Jiang Jian Guo (ZìLìGēngShēng FāFènTúQiáng JiānKǔFènDòu QínJiǎnJiànGuó). 自力更生发奋图强，艰苦奋斗勤俭建国 (自力更生發奮圖強艱苦奮鬥勤儉建國)
  - The army loves the people, the people supports the army, the army and the people unite together. Jun Ai Min, Min Yong Jun, Jun Min Tuan Jie Yi Tiao Xin (Jūn Ài​ Mín, Mín Yōng Jūn, Jūn Mín TuánJié YīTiáoXīn). 军爱民，民拥军，军民团结一条心 (軍愛民, 民擁軍, 軍民團結一條心).
  - Grasp revolution and promote production. Zhua Ge Ming, Cu Sheng Chan (Zhuā GéMìng, Cù ShēngChǎn). 抓革命，促生产 (抓革命，促生產).
  - Thorough critique of the big poisonous weed "Xiuyang (culture)". All erroneous ideas, all poisonous weeds, all ghosts and monsters, must be subjected to criticism. Mao Zedong. Che Di Pi Pan Da Du Cao "Xiu Yang." Fan Shi Cuo Wu De Si Xiang, Fan Shi Du Cao, Fan Shi Niu Gui She Shen Dou Ying Gai Jin Wing Pi Pan. Jue Bu Neng Rang Ta Men Zi You Fan Lan. Mao Ze Dong (ChèDǐ PīPàn DàDúCǎo "XiūYǎng." FánShì CuòWù de SīXiǎng, FánShì DúCǎo, FánShì NiúGuǐ ShéShén Dōu YīngGāi JìnXíng PīPàn. JuéBùNéng Ràng TāMen ZìYóu FànLàn. Máo​ Zé​dōng.). 彻底批判大毒草《修养》 凡是错误的思想，凡是毒草，凡是牛鬼蛇神，都应该进行批判，决不能让它们自由泛滥。 毛泽东 (徹底批判大毒草《修養》。凡是錯誤的思想凡是毒草凡是牛鬼蛇神都應該進行批判。決不能讓它們自由泛濫。毛澤東).
  - The force at the core leading our cause forward is the Chinese Communist Party. The theoretical basis guiding our thinking is Marxism-Leninism. Mao Zedong. Ling Dao Women Shi Ye De He Xin Li Liang Shi Zhong Guo Gong Chan Dang; Zhi Dao Wo Men Si Xiang De Li Lun Ji Chu Shi Ma Ke Si Lie Ning Zhu Yi. (LǐngDǎo WǒMen ShìYè De HéXīn LìLiang Shì Zhōng​Guó​ Gòng​Chǎn​Dǎng; ZhǐDǎo WǒMen SīXiǎng De LǐLùnJīChǔ Shì Mǎ​KèSī​ - Liè​Níng​ Zhǔ​Yì. Máo​ Zé​dōng). 领导我们事业的核心力量是中国共产党。指导我们思想的理论基础是马克思列宁主义。毛泽东 (領導我們事業的核心力量是中國共產黨; 指導我們思想的理論基礎是 馬克思列寧主義。毛澤東)
  - Carry forth mass revolutionary criticism under the guidance of the "Sixteen Articles", firmly grasp the general direction of struggle. Zai Shi Liu Tiao Zhi Yin Xia Shen Ru Kai Zhan Ge Ming Da Pi Pan, Jin Jin Zhang Wo Dou Zheng Da Fang Xiang. (Zài ShíLiùTiáo ZhǐYǐn Xià ShēnRù KāiZhǎn GéMìng Dà PīPàn, JǐnJǐn ZhǎngWò DòuZhēng Dà FāngXiàng). 在十六条指引下深入开展革命大批判，紧紧掌握斗争大方向 (在十六條指引下深入開展革命大批判, 緊緊掌握鬥爭大方向)
  - Study hard and make progress every day. Hao Hao Xue Xi Tian Tian Xiang Shang (HǎoHǎoXuéXí, TiānTiānXiàngShàng). 好好学习，天天向上 (好好學習，天天向上)
  - Closely follow Chairman Mao's great strategic plan. Jin Gen Mao Zhu Xi De Wei Da Zhan Lüe Bu Shu (JǐnGēn Máo​ Zhǔ​xí De WěiDà ZhànLüè BùShǔ). 紧跟毛主席的伟大战略部署 (緊跟毛主席的偉大戰略部署)
  - Long live the victory of Chairman Mao's revolutionary principles! Mao Zhu Xi De Ge Ming Lu Xian Sheng Li Wan Sui (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De GéMìng LùXiàn ShèngLì WànSuì). 毛主席的革命路线胜利万岁！(毛主席的革命路線勝利萬歲！)
  - Long live the success of people's war: The imperialists are bullying us in such a way that we will have to deal with them seriously. Not only must we have a powerful regular army, we must also organize contingents of the people's militia on a big scale. This will make it difficult for the imperialists to move a single inch in our country in the event of invasion. Mao Zedong. Ren Min Zhan Zheng ShengLi Wan Sui: Di Guo Zhu Yi Zhe Ru Ci Qi Fu Wo Men, She Shi Xu Yao Ren Zhen Dui Dai De. Wo Men Bu Dan You Qiang Da De Zheng Gui Jun, Wo Men Hai Yao Da Ban Min Bing Shi. Zhe Yang, Zai Di Guo Zhu Yi Qin Lüe Wo Guo De Shi Hou, Jiu Hui Shi Ta Men Cun Bu Nan Xing. Mao Ze Dong (RénMín ZhànZhēng ShèngLì WànSuì: DìGuóZhǔYì Zhě RúCǐ QīFu WǒMen, Zhè Shì XūYào RènZhēn DuìDài de。 WǒMen BùDàn Yào Yǒu QiángDà De ZhèngGuīJūn, WǒMen HáiYào Dà Bàn MínBīngShī。 ZhèYàng, Zài DìGuóZhǔYì QīnLüè WǒGuó De ShíHou, Jiù Huì Shǐ TāMen CùnBùNánXíng. Máo​ Zé​dōng). 人民战争胜利万岁：帝国主义者如此欺负我们，这是需要认真对待的。我们不但要有强大的正规军，我们还要大办民兵师。这样，在帝国主义侵略我国的时候，就会使他们寸步难行。毛泽东 (人民戰爭勝利萬歲: 帝國主義者如此欺負我們 ，這是需要認真對待的。 我們不但要有强大的正規軍，我們還要大辦民兵師。 這樣，在帝國主義侵略我國的時候，就會使他們寸步難行。-毛澤東 )
  - Long Live our great leader Chairman Mao for Ten Thousand Years! Jing Zhu Wo Men Wei Da De Ling Xiu Mao Zhu Xi Wan Shou Wu Jiang (JìngZhù WǒMen WěiDà De LǐngXiù Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànShòuWúJiāng). 敬祝我们伟大的领袖毛主席万寿无疆！( 敬祝我們偉大的領袖毛主席萬壽無疆!)
  - Unite the proletariat insurgents. Wu Chan Jie Ji Ge Ming Zao Fan Pai Lian He Qi Lai (WúChǎnJiēJí GéMìng ZàoFǎnPài LiánHé QiLai). 无产阶级革命造反派联合起来 (無產階級革命造反派聯合起來)
  - Commemorating the 28th anniversary of Chaiman Mao's inscription for Xinhua bookstore: spread the red book all around China, propagate Mao Zedong Thoughts across the world. Ji Nian Mao Zhu Xi Wei Xin Hua Shu Dian Ti Zi 28 Zhou Nian: Ba Mao Zhu Xi De Bao Shu Fa Bian Quan Guo Rang Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Pu Zhao Quan Qiu (JìNiàn Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí Wéi Xīn​Huá​ Shū​Diàn TíZì 28 ZhōuNián: Bǎ Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De BǎoShū FāBiàn QuánGuó Ràng Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng PǔZhào QuánQiú). 纪念毛主席为新华书店题字28周年：把毛主席的宝书发遍全国，让毛泽东思想普照全球 (紀念毛主席為新華書店題字28週年：把毛主席的寶書寶書發遍全國，讓毛澤東思想普照全球)
  - Flashlight, Shan Guang (ShǎnGuāng), 闪光 (閃光), January 1972
  - Highest vigilance. Bai Bei Jing Ti (BǎiBèi JǐngTì). 百倍警惕 (百倍警惕)
  - Train in big winds and waves. Dao Da Feng Da Lang Zhong Qu Duan Lian (Dào DàFēng DàLàng Zhōng Qù DuànLiàn). 到大风大浪中去锻炼 (到大風大浪中去鍛煉)
  - Take up the fighting pen, fight till the end. Jie Guo Zhan Bi, Zhan Dou Dao Di (JiēGuò Zhàn Bǐ, ZhànDòu DàoDǐ). 接过战笔，战斗到底 (接過戰筆，戰鬥到底)
  - Long Live! Long, Long Live Chairman Mao, the Reddest and Reddest Sun in Our Hearts! Wo Men Xin Zhong Zui Hong Zui Hong De Hong Tai Yang Wan Sui! Wan Wan Sui! (WǒMen XīnZhōng Zuì Hóng Zuì Hóng De Hóng TàiYang Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí WànSuì! WànWànSuì! ). 我们心中最红最红的红太阳毛主席万岁！万万岁！(我們心中最紅最紅的紅太陽毛主席萬歲! 萬萬歲! )
  - Diligently follow the "Sixteen Articles" of the Central Committee. Jian Jue An Dang Zhong Yang Shi Liu Tiao Ban Shi (JiānJué àn DǎngZhōngYāng ShíLiù Tiáo BànShì ). 坚决按党中央十六条办事 (堅決按黨中央十六條辦事)
  - Study diligently the supreme guide, faithfully carry out the supreme guide, enthusiastically propagate the supreme guide, courageously defend the supreme guide. Nu Li Xue Xi Zui Gao Zhi Shi, Re Qing Xuan Chuan Zui Gao Zhi Shi, Zhong Shi Zhi Xing Zui Gao Zhi Shi, Young Gan Han Wei Zui Gao Zhi Shi. (NǔLì Xué​Xí ZuìGāo ZhǐShì, RèQíng Xuān​Chuán ZuìGāo ZhǐShì, ZhōngShí ZhíXíng ZuìGāo ZhǐShì, YǒngGǎn HànWèi ZuìGāo ZhǐShì). 努力学习最高指示，热情宣传最高指示，忠实执行最高指示，勇敢捍卫最高指示。 (努力學習最高指示，熱情宣傳最高指示，忠實執行最高指示，勇敢捍衛最高指示。)
  - You must pay attention to state affairs and carry the great proletarian cultural revolution through to the end! Mao Zedong. Ni Men Yao Guan Xin Guo Jia Da Shi, Yao Ba Wu Chan Jie Ji Wen Hua Da Ge Ming Jin Xing Dao Di! Mao Ze Dong (NǐMen Yào GuānXīn GuóJiā DàShì, Yào Bǎ WúChǎnJiēJí Wén​Huà​ Dà​Gé​Mìng JìnXíng DàoDǐ! Máo​ Zé​dōng.) 你们要关心国家大事，要把无产阶级文化大革命进行到底！毛泽东 (你們要關心國家大事，要把無產階級文化大革命進行到底！ 毛澤東)
  - Firm support of the PLA! Always trust the PLA! Learn modestly from the PLA! Jian Jue Yong Hu Jie Fang Jun! Yong Yuan Xiang Xin Jie Fang Jun! Xu Xin Xue Xi Jie Fang Jun! (JiānJué YōngHù Jiě​Fàng​Jūn! YǒngYuǎn XiāngXìn Jiě​Fàng​Jūn! XūXīn XuéXí Jiě​Fàng​Jūn!) 坚决拥护解放军！永远相信解放军！虚心学习解放军！(堅決擁護解放軍! 永遠相信解放軍! 虛心學習解放軍!)
  - Hold high the great red banner of Mao Zedong to carry the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution to the end! Gao Ju Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Wei Da Hong Qi Ba Wu Chan Jie Ji Wen Hua Da Ge Ming Jin Xing Dao Di (GāoJǔ Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng WěiDà HóngQí Bǎ WúChǎnJiēJí Wén​Huà​ Dà​Gé​Mìng​ JìnXíng DàoDǐ). 高举毛泽东思想伟大红旗 把无产阶级文化大革命进行到底 (高舉毛澤東思想偉大紅旗把無產階級文化大革命進行到底)
  - Read Chairman Mao's book, listen to Chairman Mao's words, follow Chairman Mao's orders. Lin Biao. Du Mao Zhu Xi De Shu, Ting Mao Zhu Xi De Hua, Zhao Mao Zhu Xi De Zhi Shi Ban Shi. Lin Biao. (Dú Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Shū, Tīng Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Huà, Zhào Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De ZhǐShì BànShì. Lín​ Biāo.). 读毛主席的书，听毛主席的话，照毛主席的指示办事。 林彪 (讀毛主席的書，聽毛主席的話，照毛主席的指示辦事。 林彪)
  - Cheer for China's first successful hydrogen bomb detonation! Our great leader Chairman Mao pointed out as early as June 1958 that building atomic and hydrogen bombs would absolutely be possible in ten years' time. Re Lie Huan Hu Wo Guo Di Yi Ke Qing Dan Bao Zha Cheng Gong! Wo Men Wei Da Ling Xiu Mao Zhu Xi Zao Zai Yi Ju Wu Ba Nian Liu Yue Jiu Zhi Chu Gao Yi Dian Yuan Zi Dan Qing Dan, Wo Kan Shi Nian Gong Fu Wan Quan Ke Neng (RèLiè HuānHū WǒGuó DìYī Kē QīngDàn BàoZhà ChéngGōng! WǒMen WěiDà LǐngXiù Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí ZǎoZài Yī Jiǔ Wǔ Bā Nián Liù​Yuè Jiù ZhǐChū Gǎo YīDiǎn YuánZǐDàn QīngDàn, Wǒ Kàn Shí Nián GōngFu WánQuán Kě​Néng). 热烈欢呼我国第一颗氢弹爆炸成功！我们伟大领袖毛主席早在一九五八年六月就指出：搞一点原子弹、氢弹，我看十年工夫完全可能。(熱烈歡呼我國第一顆氫彈爆炸成功！我們偉大領袖毛主席早在一九五八年六月就指出：搞一點原子彈，氫彈，我看十年工夫完全可能。)
  - Chairman Mao says: "You should pay attention to state affairs and carry the great proletarian cultural revolution through to the end!" Mao Zhu Xi Shuo: "Ni Men Yao Guan Xin Guo Jia Da Shi, Yao Ba Wu Chan Jie Ji Wen Hua Da Ge Ming Jin Xing Dao Di!" (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí Shuō: "NǐMen Yào GuānXīn GuóJiā DàShì, Yào Bǎ WúChǎnJiēJí Wén​Huà​ Dà​Gé​Mìng JìnXíng DàoDǐ!"). 毛主席说：“你们要关心国家大事，把无产阶级文化大革命进行到底！” (毛主席説: "你們要關心國家大事，要把無產階級文化大革命進行到底!")
  - Our great tutor, great leader, great commander-in-chief and great helmsman Chairman Mao is reviewing the troops on the National Day parade. Wo Men Wei Da De Dao Shi, Wei Da De Ling Xiu, Wei Da De Tong Shuai, Wei Da De Duo Shou Mao Zhu Xi Zai Tian An Men Cheng Lou Shang Jian Yue Guo Qing You Xing Da Jun. (WǒMen WěiDà De DǎoShī, WěiDà De LǐngXiù, WěiDà De TǒngShuài, WěiDà De DuòShǒu Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí Zài Tiān​'ān​Mén ChéngLóu Shàng JiǎnYuè Guó​Qìng YóuXíng DàJūn). 我们伟大的导师，伟大的领袖，伟大的统帅，伟大的舵手 毛主席在天安门城楼上检阅国庆游行大军 (我們偉大的導師，偉大的領袖， 偉大的統帥， 偉大的舵手毛主席在天安門城樓上檢閱國慶遊行大軍。)
  - Great leader Chairman Mao waves to us. Wei Da Ling Xiu Mao Zhu Xi Xiang Wo Men Hui Shou (WěiDà LǐngXiù Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí Xiàng WǒMen HuīShǒu). 伟大领袖毛主席向我们挥手 ( 偉大領袖毛主席向我們揮手)
  - Model Yourself After Comrade Jiao Yulu and Become Chairman Mao's Good Student. Be Infinitely Faithful to the Revolution and Be Sincerely Devoted to the People. Yi Jiao Yu Lu Tong Zhi Wei Bang Yang, Zuo Mao Zhu Xi De Hao Xue Sheng, Dui Ge Ming Wu Xian Zhong Cheng, Wei Ren Min Ju Gong Kin Cui. (Yǐ Jiāo Yù Lù TóngZhì Wéi BǎngYàng, Zuò Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De Hǎo XuéSheng, Duì GéMìng WúXiàn ZhōngChéng, Wéi RénMín JūGōngJìnCuì.). 以焦裕禄同志为榜样，做毛主席的好学生，对革命无限忠诚，为人民鞠躬尽瘁。(以焦裕祿同志为榜樣，做毛主席的好學生，對革命無限忠誠，為人民鞠躬盡瘁。)
  - Rise up and Beat the Drowning Dog with the Staff of Mao Zedong Thought. Fen Qi Mao Ze Dong Si Xiang Qian Jun Bang Tong Da Luo Shui Gou. (FènQǐ Máo​ Zé​Dōng​ Sī​Xiǎng QiānJūnBàng TòngDǎ LuòShuǐGǒu). 奋起毛泽东思想千钧棒痛打落水狗 (奮起毛澤東思想千鈞棒痛打落水狗)
  - Study the "Three Old Articles" as your motto, destroy self-interest and promote devotion to the public interest to revolutionize your thoughts. Yao Ba Lao San Pian ZZuo Wei Zuo You Ming Lai Xue, Po Si Li Gong Shi Xian Si Xiang Ge Ming Hua (Yào Bǎ LǎoSānPiān ZuòWéi ZuòYòuMíng Lái Xué, Pò SīLì Gōng ShíXiàn SīXiǎng GéMìng Huà). 要把“老三篇”作为座右铭来学，破私立公实现思想革命化。(要把老三篇作為座右銘來學，破私立公實現思想革命化。)
  - Develop the spirit of "carrying the load on your back" to serve the people with all your heart and all your mind. Fa Yang Bei Lou Jing Shen Quan Xin Quan Yi Wei Ren Min Fu Wu. (FāYáng BēiLǒu JīngShén QuánXīnQuánYì Wèi RénMín FúWù). 发扬“背篓精神”全心全意为人民服务 (發揚背簍精神全心全意為人民服務)
  - Long live the victory of Chairman Mao's political line in literature and art! Commemorating the 25th anniversary of the publication of "Talks at the Yan'an Forum on Literature and Art." Mao Zhu Xi De Wen Yi Lu Xian Sheng Li Wan Sui! Ji Nian 《Zai Yan An Wen Yi Zuo Tan Hui Shang De Jiang Hua》Fa Biao Er Shi Wu Zhou Nian (Máo​ Zhǔ​Xí De WénYì LùXiàn ShèngLì WànSuì! JìNiàn 《Zài Yán​'ān WénYì ZuòTánHuì Shàng De JiǎngHuà》 FāBiǎo èrShíWǔ ZhōuNián). 毛主席的文艺路线胜利万岁！纪念《在延安文艺座谈会上的讲话》发表二十五周年 (毛主席的文藝路線勝利萬歲！紀念 《在延安文藝座談會上的講話》 發表二十五週年)